OWAIS ABBASI

owais.abbasi9@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/owaisabbasi89/

Contact: +923012316329

Location: Karachi, Pakistan (willing to relocate)



OBJECTIVE:

Seeking an entry-level position as a Data Engineer or a Data Analyst, leveraging my four years of experience in Accounting and Financial Reporting. By combining this background with Data Analytics and Data Engineering, I offer employers a valuable and diverse skill set.

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS:

- Supervised Machine Learning (Instructor: DeepLearning.ai)
- Mathematics for Machine Learning and Data Science Specialization (Instructor: DeepLearning.ai)
- Python Data Structures (Instructor: University of Michigan)
- Data Visualization and Dashboards with Excel and Cognos (Instructor: IBM)
- Excel Basics for Data Analysis (Instructor: IBM)
- Introduction to Data Analytics (Instructor: IBM)

Coursera

SKILLS:

Mathematics, Machine Learning, Data Science, Python Programming, Machine Learning Algorithms, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Data Operations, Statistical Analysis, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression for Classification, Regularization to Avoid Over fitting, Gradient Descent, Data Structures, Pivot Table

EXPERIENCE:

Federal Board of Revenue, Government of Pakistan	Data Supervisor in Data Processing Centre, Computer Wing	(Sep, 2016 to Current) 7 years
• Leads a team of five subordinates in supervising timely data entry tasks with a strong attention to detail,		

- Leads a team of five subordinates in supervising timely data entry tasks with a strong attention to detail
 ensuring accuracy and consistency in records.
- Collaborate with colleagues to streamline data management processes, contributing to improved efficiency and data quality.

Mishanz Private Limited	Senior Accounts Executive in	(Apr, 2010 to Nov, 2011 and Mar,
	Accounts Department	2013 to Aug, 2015) 4 years

- Managed a team of three Accounts Officers, reporting to the CFO, with a strong emphasis on prioritizing financial reporting accuracy and interpretation.
- Responsibilities included overseeing General Journal Entries, Ledger Reconciliation, and managing Receivables and Payables Aging, along with Bank Reconciliation.
- Proficient in the Sidat Hyder Financials ERP, specializing in the General Ledger and Fixed Assets Management System Modules, and enhancing financial reporting skills.

EDUCATION:

•	CFA Level-I	CFA Institute, USA	2018
•	Masters in Economics and Finance	University of Karachi	2015
•	Bachelors of Commerce	University of Karachi	2010
•	CA-Foundation	Institute of Chartered	2010
		Accountants of Pakistan	